SAIFAHMAD PIRJADE FULL STACK DEVELOPER



+91 9503495521



Mumbai



saif.pirjade@gmail.com



LinkedIn: esaifpirjade

I'm a full stack developer Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable backend and frontend development requirements. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements. Able to handle any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 4 years of related experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Fameworks: NodeJs, ReactJS, AngularJs,

VueJs, Laravel

Languages: JavaScript, C#, C++, PHP,

Python, HTML

Cloud Platform: AWS and Google Cloud

Version Control System: Git, Bitbucket

Other Skills: NGinx, JQuery, Ajax, CSS

OS: Mac Os, Linux, Windows

Database: MySQL, MongoDB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

BINARY NUMBERS | MUMBAI | 2017 - PRESENT

A full service product engineering IT company offering web and app development services and next generation solutions for small and large businesses across the world.

- Leads Management System For DAMAC Properties Dubai: Implemented backend to collect/filter/manage marketing data from hubspot, Google WebHook & facebook & dynamically synced with salesforce. Improved success rate and optimized code-base.
- *CMS/Website Builder For DAMAC Properties Dubai:* Created backend to dynamically create landing pages/accelerated-mobile-pages and created REST API for dynamic content mapping based on business-rules.
- *Ticketak For UAE:* Conducted the requirement for websites & developed a working Webpack based single page VueJs Application from scratch. Integrated the REST API to communicate backend for dynamic content. developed dashboard to handle various CURD operation using VueJs.
- *GoGoCinema For GDC Technology Limited Singapore:* Responsible for all parts of the dev process, including planning, design development, testing and maintenance. Used VueJs as a framework to develop a PWA application which can bind data to specific views and synchronise data with the server.
- Boupon For Jatra International Private Ltd: Created ecommerce platform from mobile recharge and coupons. Worked on REST API's as well as Node framework for backend services, Used MongoDB for database services. developed single VueJs Application for frontend.

- **BRIJ For In-house:** Created the fully customisable cinema system. Implemented backend using NodeJs to mange all movies/seats/booking/FnB data as per cinemas & created reusable codes & modules to facilitate smooth future usage. Created Web App and Engineered dynamic components using VueJs.
- *Empire Cinemas For Saudi Arabia, Lebanon, Iraq:* Responsibilities develop/program the new functionality and features in line with functional specification and as per business requirements. Involved with bug fixing on functionality, performance and other related issues with JavaScript and VueJs.
- *MissMalini For missmalini.com India:* Involved with bug fixing on functionality, performance and other related issues with JavaScript and ReactJs. Modified existing modules, code & created reusable component with a dynamic data.
- **People Matters cohort For People Matters Media:** Designed single page web app structure and developed from scratch using VueJs. Worked with REST API's integration using axios to fetch the dynamic content and interact with backend for web app.

SENIOR WEB & MOBILE APP DEVELOPER

FOREHOTEL | MUMBAI | 2017 - 2017

A ForeHotel company has created the product to find jobs in the hospitality industry for job seekers. The company has created the two mobile apps.

Projects: ForeHotels, ForeHotels Recruiter.

Environment: Php, HTML, JQuery, Typescript, Javascript, Mysql.

- Developed Web App using Core PHP and performed up-gradation on existing modules.
- Developed ForeHotels Employee and ForeHotels Recruiter Hybrid Mobile Application using Ionic v2 framework(Cordova), AngularJS, typescript, HTML 5 and SCSS.
- Created API's for web and mobile app using NodeJs and Performed up-gradation on existing modules.
- Created a new design for a mobile app using Ionic components and enhanced existing design.

WEB & MOBILE APP DEVELOPER

ILEX SQUARE INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY & SERVICES | MUMBAI | 2016 - 2017

A complete web solutions company specialising in web development, App Development (android, iOS, windows Phone), BPM solutions, E-Commerce website creation etc.

Projects: Avadh Metal Web Application, Restonza Mobile App, Navicarna Mobile App, Deezeed. Environment: Php, HTML, Java, JQuery, Javascript, Typescript, Mysql, MongoDB.

- Appointed as a Web developer and Mobile Application developer to develop web pages and mobile apps by using various scripting languages.
- Spearheaded three projects within a given period in the capacity of Core Engineers.
- Developed Web Apps, dashboards and online applications by using various scripting.
- Created custom mobile applications using native technologies as per client specifications.
- Created a new design for a web app using HTML and Media Query and enhanced existing design.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATIONS FROM YCMOU IN YEAR 2014.

H.S.C. FROM KOLHAPUR BOARD, MAHARASHTRA IN YEAR 2009.